okay so we're doing class when is that
three of this course and before he
starts on the three principal paths
Jensen kapa makes a big deal that you
should have a teacher you should have a
qualified teacher and because you are in
a teacher training this is maybe a very
important class for you not what to look
for in a teacher but what to be in a
teacher okay and the list is impossible
but teach anyway okay you can't be such
a good person it's impossible but there
are ten qualities of a real teacher
authentic teacher okay and we're gonna
go through those 10 qualities tonight
I'm gonna take about an hour
we won't go probably to the flow
document of the 18 courses we'll start
that again tomorrow because it's a very
good luck that today is a holy day tenth
day of the month we call Saito
it's a diamond way holiday today big
twice a month today very big holiday and
we decided to do the offering to Lamas
which is I think the most holy prayer in
Tibet I remember the first time I met
monks and nuns I walked into our Lama
chopped up by accident and I didn't know
what was going on but it felt really
good you know
so tonight we'll do this offering and
the main thing about this all rituals
they can either be meaningless or they
can be meaningful okay I'll show you the
meaning okay
okay trust me a lot of people do it in
the monastery okay so that's the way not
to do a ritual okay
and tonight we're gonna do namah Shiva
to do it correct me it doesn't matter
what you say and it doesn't matter if
you know the language and it doesn't
matter if you finish the prayer it just
matters that you think about your
teachers in your life okay start with
your mom go to your dad all your school
teachers all your ex-husbands and wife
who taught you a lot by giving you such
trouble and then you know work your way
up to your spiritual teachers okay if
your mind is thinking tonight about
gratitude for your teachers then you did
the ceremony and if you retouch the
recited perfectly in Tibetan and you
close your eyes and go like that but
you're thinking about eating more snacks
after the ritual then you didn't do Lama
Champa okay so you did Lama cheaper if
you think about your teachers and be
grateful to your mom be grateful to then
all your teachers and your knife okay
and it's nice to make a list in your
mind some of those teachers you didn't
think about them for many years so
tonight during the ritual do a booty
call
Charcot review meditation about all the
teachers in your night okay then you did
not mature per then you deserve the
offerings afterwards okay okay this is
probably one of the most important
classes of all the ACI courses and this
is the class where poppin corn Puccini
in his commentary explains what is a
llamas if you go shopping for a llama
what should you look for and it's an
important list okay so it has ten
parts okay very famous by the way
there's a diamond way edition of ten
more but we're not going to do it
tonight okay
someday you have to learn those okay in
this I believe it's in the same verse
actually okay here's the first one say -
whaa - whaa do what you know do noir
which means vinaya which means to tame a
wild horse okay this is the past tense
tamed uh okay there llama already beat
them up until they're a nice person
everybody asked me why are Tibetan monks
so polite I say it's a rosary they say
what do you mean I said which oh okay if
you do anything wrong in the monastery
they hit you with a rosary hard on the
head and you get the blessing of a these
red dots and everyone makes fun of you
for all day if you do something really
bad they use a belt or an electrical
cord or a fan belt from an engine and
that's quite an experience so anyway
willful anymore but in this poem in this
list it refers to keeps their morality
keeps their ethical life okay they avoid
those ten bad deeds they don't kill
people or animals or fetuses they don't
steal things over the the classic Texas
over the cost of a good sweater so ten
dollars I don't hmm okay no sexual
misconduct which is mainly hurting other
people's marriage or relationship okay
no lying the big number one lie is to
say you saw emptiness and you didn't see
emptiness or to say you met my jury
yesterday and you didn't meet my dresser
so these are called the big lie then we
call splitting up people with your
speech you know so mark you know Stanley
he really likes you and despite what he
said yesterday to me privately you see
okay then
those words will create doubt in mark's
mind Oh what did Stanley say about me
and then already I split them okay it's
not true okay I'm just giving an example
he's like hmm okay so that's very easy
to make that mistake and split up
friends okay then next one is called
harsh words it's like to say stupid or
idiot or fun phone or call people bad
names my roommate in college we had
nickname for each other I'm sorry excuse
me but my name was and he
called me and I call him
something else which I cannot say and
but with great love and with great
affection okay right so it doesn't
depend on the word it depends on the
motivation right how do you feel if you
can say have a nice day and it means to
go to hell all right have a nice day you
know so it doesn't matter what you say
it matters how you say it right so
that's number one 6 and then wasted talk
talking about nothing wasting time
talking
Artie Shaw said once you get more than
one person in the room you will do this
maybe you could do it by yourself I
don't know we could try ok waste your
time talking and it's very very common
ok then the eight nine and ten are the
most serious right
it is what be unhappy when other people
get something nice okay be jealous or
unhappy if it's in the top ten of 84,000
bad deeds it must be something we all do
many times every day without knowing it
okay like oh oh really that guy had a
car accident oh I'm so sorry did he cut
off anything you know like we have this
interest about disasters right how many
people died in the bombing you know how
did they die and and you have this weird
human nature to be interested in other
people's problems and to be jealous when
other people have something good okay
even your best friend you know if they
get a very handsome boyfriend you're
like oh congratulations you know it
means you're really not very happy okay
number nine okay it's two opposite
what's that
yeah be happy when when something bad
happens to somebody okay they the guy
you don't like lost he went bankrupt and
you're like oh I'm so sorry you know
okay
number ten yeah
to put it simply you can say don't don't
understand the pen don't accept Karma I
don't accept future life past life okay
like that so the first quality out of
the ten qualities of a llama is they
keep those ten very well they keep those
ten very well I was thinking about a few
a CI teachers I know who failed who
failed very badly and the one I'm
thinking of they failed because they
were not keeping the morality number
three but there were dangerous signs
long before that they were not careful
with people's money
or you know they were lying sometimes
and I have a feeling that all ten of
these bad deeds support each other so if
you if you find a person that you want
to be your teacher be strict okay don't
take a teacher easily it's much more
serious than getting married it's much
more seriously getting married I'm
talking about formal relationship with a
teacher you see because in Buddhism it's
a very it's a connection that lasts many
lifetimes so you have to be careful who
you make a connection to it's my hope
and my intention that people who come to
your classes are not required to take
you as a Lama
okay they are not required to say I
commit to you for a thousand lifetimes
or something because they just met you
they know you for five minutes
they just you're just teaching the first
class so I think it's unfair to say this
person is your Lama for the next
thousand lifetimes you can't even you
know smile in front of them you will
break your morality you know like I I
think the way it should work in a CI is
a you teach and you're gonna teach for
free you can have offerings if they
offer offerings okay they're most likely
to offer an apple and some bananas and
you have to pay the airfare and you
offer the airfare to American Airlines
you offer the banana to American
Airlines and it doesn't work out but
anyway we'll talk about it later there's
a financial policy for ACI but I it's my
intention that when you become an ACI
teacher you don't become their lama
automatically if they want you to be
their Lama
that's fine they can say you know
jasmine I love you I've been coming to
your classes for six months and I'm
ready to make this commitment
with you and that's fine but I think
just because you teach the class it
shouldn't be so heavy for them as a
llama relationship okay because it's a
very it's like getting married it's more
important than getting married okay all
right so that's the first thing we're
talking don't make that commitment of
Lama and disciple right teacher student
Lama disciple different right don't make
this commitment easily you know check
the personnel okay
countless married couples get divorced
you know the numbers in America it's
about 65 percent get divorce they
interviewed the other 35 percent are you
happy two-thirds said no which means
ninety percent of couples aren't happy
how come you didn't get divorced we have
kids okay so it means you didn't check
the personnel before you got married
okay so people I'm heard a radio
interview with some country music singer
I forget his name like a week ago he's
been married seven times and the
announcer said he's been married seven
times he got six divorces and the guy
goes what he says well actually last
week it's a seven so don't get married
to someone after you know them for half
an hour okay and don't take someone as a
mama there's a young monk coming with my
teacher from the monastery you know and
they asked me do you want him to teach
he's a gadget candidate and I said no
and they said why not and I said I don't
know him I don't know I don't know his
private life you know 80 percent of the
monks I brought to America I got about
eight green cards you don't know how
long that takes to do the paperwork
and the money in six of them ran away
with some girl or something like I I
don't want I don't know this person they
said you want him to give a lecture I
said no let me get to know him first you
know I probably he's a nice guy
but don't make this relationship and
don't ask someone to teach you until you
check them out Artesia took 11 months 12
months - how long to sail to Indonesia
Sumatra over a year when he got there he
didn't go to the teacher he checked him
out for how many months I forgot well
traditionally it can be 12 years okay
there's a joke in Tibet you know the guy
went checked his Lama out for 12 years
and then he said he went too long he
said you're so lucky he said what I
decided to take you as my Lama I checked
you out for 12 years you pass and the
lamas like well now I'm gonna check you
out for 12 years so come back in 12 hour
let you know okay so you know it's
tradition to just be very very careful
and countless people have made a
commitment to a llama and they didn't
know them they just met them there's
llamas giving tantric initiations for
$25.00
you never met them
you're supposed to study with someone
like seven eight years before you can
talk about Tantra you see and they're
just give an announcement you know I'm
giving this year next year $35 $25 if
you pay early you know my lama was very
upset about that stuff okay so be
careful check them check them up okay
don't be in a rush you will get hurt you
you will be disappointed okay okay so
first thing you're looking for you're
looking for ten things number one are
they honest are they ethical
okay and if they're a little bit
unethical in their finances but they
seem okay in their sexual life don't
don't take them as a teacher okay if
there's a problem while we're here
there's a problem over here okay that's
the nature of ethics okay all right mmm
ii say she wha what's it mean in
sunscreen shanti we did it in class
today we had a great class with Nicole
where are you yeah we had a great class
I feel so good afternoon nice okay so
anyway she what means peace peaceful
they should be peaceful okay but it's a
code word for they have good meditation
okay they have good meditation they
practice meditation every day they work
hard and they have good meditation okay
all right you can tell if a person has
good meditation they do things carefully
they do things calmly they don't get
upset easily they are very good at
problem-solving personal problems
business problems because they have
their mind this is running on a better
level okay so you can tell if a person
looks nervous
or they get angry easily or they get
upset easily or they have lots of
tension and problems around them it
doesn't matter if they're sitting on a
cushion every day they're probably not
meditating okay so just check the person
now be smart okay check them out they
they say oh this is a great meditation
master I met one like that not Tibetan
okay and they say he sat in the snow for
six days meditating you know and I
actually went to him and stayed a couple
days to learn and it was very unpleasant
he was very angry and nervous and okay
so check him out okay it they're
meditating
there's there's just behavior there
science should be behavior science
they're peaceful they don't get upset
easily
there was a great meditator named multi
Rinpoche and I had the honour to spend
some time with him we were driving
through the Indian countryside and the
car broke which is very unusual in India
right Andres and and the you know we got
out and he's this old you know llama and
and we stood we all stood around the
engine you know and the Indian driver
was trying to fix it and and Lahti
remember said to me know what's this
thing do I said that's a carburetor it
cleans the air you know and he says
what's this thing do well that's the gas
pump what's this thing do oh that's the
battery and he looks and he says the
problem is here and we fixed it he never
saw an engine in his life okay so if
you're meditating
you should have super intelligent and
you solve problems easily with other
people okay if a person is always
fighting with other people if there's
always tension around them if they're
always nervous if it always late
I mean sometimes - okay you know if
they're just not organized they're not
responsible they're probably not
meditating okay what's that famous ACI
joke I don't know what kind of
meditation she's teaching but I don't
want to learn it okay so check that they
are meditating okay third quality is
called near she say near she by the way
there's a poem douching sheila near
she's longer - it's very famous this is
from a poem and it's a tradition for
root lama after their student becomes a
good lama they will write a long life
prayer for them a poem for their long
life and the long life prayer for my
teacher was written by two German Roger
who wrote down this bomb room and it's
very beautiful and it he got all these
ten in there he said you know to she was
no machine deal was she when you're seen
only took very famous okay the next one
is called near she near she means super
peaceful okay super peaceful what's
number two peaceful okay
what's number one controlled you know
they're controlled they don't break
their morality okay
they have self control like a well tenth
or do one okay and number three is near
she means total totally peaceful and
that means they saw emptiness directly
or they can teach it correctly they
studied it they studied the great books
okay they understand emptiness correctly
it's best if they saw it directly but
that's extremely rare okay it's best if
they have seen it directly but if you if
you can't find one just find one who can
teach it correctly and and what's
interesting in that some cop on lineage
is that the emptiness teachings have
been passed on correctly even by
generations of people who didn't see it
directly okay they're so strict with the
translation and they're so strict with
not mixing up chocolate cake and Mabo
tofu that I can tell you the teachings
are completely 100% correct
okay so if you can find a lineage like
that even if the person didn't see it
directly it's okay they will make a good
teacher
okay all right if they're not mixing
Mabo tofu in the chocolate cake okay
okay number four say you and then
da yen 10 sapa it's pretty simple but
it's something you might not think about
the teacher should know more than the
students okay like I feel stupid when I
go to an atoll when an atoll comes to my
yoga class right I feel stupid because
he's he's a much better yoga teacher
than me you know I just have to teach
the class and then I'm like don't come
to my class it's like I want to come
it'll be fun I said yeah but it's
uncomfortable for me okay so obviously
you should try to find a teacher who
who's better than you I was on the
tennis team in high school
so for four years
what he call competing and during the
season and the practice season the
practice seasons about three or four
months the coach made a rule that we
couldn't play okay number one we
couldn't play with a girl against a girl
and we number two we couldn't play
against anyone who was not better than
us you see in an interesting
same with llama ok don't play with
someone who's not better than you okay
they should know more their meditation
should be better their ethics should be
better their kindness should be all
those qualities should be better because
otherwise you're gonna get bad you're
gonna go down you know if their ethics
are not so good but they're magic mica
is very good your money makers gonna go
up and your ethics gonna go down okay
you do you know what the SATA is SATA
ism is a mold like my I've been to
Amitabha mold and you put the clay you
put the clay in and then you pull it out
and it looks like Amitabh ah you see a
little images like that and then you
bake it and you keep it on your altar
states called Saturn the mold is called
SATA the teacher is a satyr the student
is the clay
they're going to come out just like the
teacher okay so if their ethics is not
so good and their ma jamika is very good
you're gonna come out and like that and
I've seen it many many times in the
monastery what's fun when you go to the
Olympics there's a debate on Olympics
every year one month
it's called Joong Geun Cho and it's a
competition between the monasteries you
know and it's very heavy very very heavy
one month debate sometimes all night
Sengkang all night debate until dawn and
you're debating and what's cool is you
can debate people the second year and
you say oh your teachers gives you
jumpers thank you from Saturday isn't he
and they're like yeah how do you know
because the student comes out like the
teacher you know what's cool you can
debate somebody that you don't know and
from another monastery and then after
like a half hour you say I know who your
teacher is you see because the student
comes out like that SATA the student
comes on with you so don't go to a
teacher who is worse than you if their
meditations worse than you or their
ethics is worse than you or their mother
maker is worse than yours okay I'll tell
you something interesting okay
I'm not bragging but I am I went to give
a DCI program in Bangalore India to a
bunch of business people and my
monastery is a nine-hour drive which is
not too far and gassy loads are my old
house teacher he came to visit during
the talk and he brought three gassy
candidates with him these are high high
guessing candidates and hustle was with
me where are you right and ohrid was
there and scar and
Adam and I forget someone asked - Latoya
question and one of the guest candidates
answered and then or Reid said but isn't
it like this and then hassle said I
think it's like this too you know and
they debated the three Geshe candidates
they beat their ass okay all right I was
like okay and the Geisha character like
okay just to warn you I mean the the the
quality of teaching the quality of the
ACI courses is very high it's it's you
can stand up to it get here if you study
the Acer courses and if they can speak
English or you know Chinese or whatever
you will you would you'll do be like
like hah so they should have given you a
gift that day but you know I was very
proud of him okay
so what I mean is don't assume a person
who has a red robe or a yellow robe or a
great world or who went to the Geisha
course knows more than you check them
out check them out ask them tough
questions okay and see what they say
unfortunately like in all universities
in the monastery it sometimes happens
that people memorize everything but they
don't understand it you know and they
don't really question it so sometimes
foreigners or non gushy nobody call non
ordained people can deal i has learned
more than I get here by questioning
things you seen I mean in a normal way
okay so don't just because a person has
a robe on check them out okay or
somebody says they're famous check them
out
there's lots of famous people who became
unfamous later infamous okay all right
okay so that's number one for you know
check them out make sure they know more
than you you might spend a couple years
of them and find out you didn't learn
anything new
okay really okay so be be demanding okay
your mental real estate is irreplaceable
you have so many hours in your life the
number of breaths you will take has a
number and don't waste it okay check the
people out don't go and sit there for a
year and find out they they weren't
qualified okay check them out
all right number what five say some
chick Jim Jim means they work hard what
kind of hard work they work hard for
their students
okay they work hard for their students
okay and they think it's fun to teach
people and to help their students you
you call them up at midnight Nicole I'm
sorry I'm not supposed to say who
someone called me up in China at three
o'clock in the morning they said my
husband's dying next to me right now
what do I do
you know and we talked it out and he
died and so you gotta be there for your
students right that's a big thing okay
like you don't say come on it's three
o'clock in the morning
tell them not to die till tomorrow you
know okay all right so Sanjay means they
enjoy the trouble of teaching people
okay they enjoy helping people
okay you want to find a crazy person
like that like John Brady you know you
know somebody says can you fly to
Singapore and teach that class we missed
and John's like yeah sure you know
so you gotta find someone who really
enjoys helping people okay and not who's
not someone who doesn't want to give
okay we call P Q P Q means uh they don't
want to give everything they don't want
to give all their time they don't want
to give their heart they hold back from
the student you don't want to teach her
like that okay you want to teach you who
do anything for you okay my llama was
like that number six okay
I said long he took nokia choke longer
chip means they are rich in Jing they
have lots of scriptural knowledge they
know all the great books they've studied
them they've memorized them they spent
time with them they worked hard okay and
you never finish okay my the teacher who
taught me Pomona which is clear thinking
he was on his deathbed he was dying in
the hospital he was his last day of his
life and I went to see him because I was
taking him to doctors for many years and
translating and so I said you know guess
live this looks like and he says yeah
this is it and there was this lump on
his chest you know I said what's going
on what's that and he took the sheet off
and it's pramana vertica commenting for
beginning monks okay for 15 year old
monks it's the pramana vantika
commentary we call the green book it's
the one that Adam is translating and
he's got it on his chest he's dying you
know I'm like what's going on just know
he said hey you know I gotta go
somewhere I'm also had my logic fresh
you know you know I just wanted freshen
up on it cuz tomorrow who knows where
I'll be you know I can't take the book
with me
and he gave me the book and I I still
have it and we're translating it in
Sedona and it's very beautiful okay so
find a teacher like that okay
I heard Xiao ping has a teacher I met
his wife recently and we had tea
together and she was complaining that
the bed was half filled with books all
the time like there wasn't room for her
and I was like what's the problem he's
got like 50,000 books in the house you
know you walk to the bathroom and a pile
of books falls on you and you want
somebody like that okay someone who
really loves the books like John Brady
ACIP master okay all right they are rich
in the book you asked my question that's
all you know that's chandrakirti verse
40 you know it's in their mind okay
all right I went to a class by like a
psychology person late recently someone
asked me to go and I was being polite
and I said are okay and I went and they
said don't think with your head think
with your heart you know you won't get
enlightened by thinking you know to do
everything with your heart you know then
we had lunch together the next day and
I'm like well in our tradition the way
you get to your heart is through your
brain you see you figure out emptiness
and then you know you have to love
people you see I mean but you need the
it's not wrong and Buddhism to to learn
all the scriptures and to work to your
heart to do the head okay the heart
without the head is an unsteady creature
it can change very easily
so the head makes the heart strong okay
alright number what are we on seven say
De Niro talk pain erupt Oh Danny laptop
means specifically okay number three was
what
yeah they understand the seat system for
example they understand emptiness okay
number seven means they have seen it
directly for sure or very close or they
know about it very well okay so he
repeated number seven kind of repeats
number three okay but it's more specific
Janie means emptiness tattva and rub
dope means mister dictionary rub the
tapa with an ass yeah super understood
super realized emptiness okay so you're
looking for someone like that there's a
tradition in Buddhism that says for
disciples who are not so intelligent
teach them one or two proofs of
emptiness and stop and but if you meet a
very good disciple teach them a thousand
proofs of emptiness teach them emptiness
from a thousand different ways a
thousand different arguments okay and we
don't consider it too much information
we consider it more strong okay like I
don't know many many many proofs of
emptiness in Madhumita okay Buddha
Buddha taught by the way all those five
toppings come from Buddha right Buddha
taught countless proofs for emptiness
and and you should know them and you
should have them in your toolkit and you
should find a teacher who knows them
okay they shouldn't no one kind of
emptiness or or some by the way if if I
were you if I were as young as candy lie
and I was looking for a teacher
I would talk to them about emptiness for
half an hour
and if they don't say what you heard
here I wouldn't take them as a teacher
okay and and I have to say that the
level of understanding the kitchen I
don't think you'll find it almost
anywhere in the world
okay it sounds simple Oh dependent
origination is yelling at the kids it
sounds simple but when you're looking
for a teacher don't be satisfied unless
that teacher can take that argument to
the kitchen if they can't explain
Buddhism in the kitchen what's the sons
are in the kitchen yeah y'all bad you
know okay if they can't explain
emptiness in the kitchen they don't know
anything this okay I got it okay all
right we were talking in China soft
power right amazing program amazing
those two kids my two kids Stanley and
Allison grant knock grandkids we
graduated they started this program
called China South are they teach
business executives the ancient classics
and how to use them in business for the
one belt one road when China goes out to
the world these people are like the
heroes of Chinese culture and Wow they
they understand those kitchens so dang
well you know it's unbelievable it's
really unbelievable and I see more
understanding there than I see in the
monastery you know in that room it's
amazing you know so look for that kind
of person
okay who can bring it to the real world
okay all right
number one eight stay mark Kingdon
mark and then my mommy is teaching okay
k-means master teaching master dan means
they have this quality so ma k-means
very good teacher okay and it often
happens in things like music you know
this guy's a famous piano player but he
can't teach anybody you see sometimes
they're a very good teacher and they're
a lousy piano player and then you can't
learn anything either you want to find
the best piano player who's also the
best teacher
so that's rare okay you want to find the
master of buddhism but who can teach it
to people okay and the main quality that
they list in the scriptures is that they
are able to fit the level of their
teaching to the level of the student
which might result in a whole bunch of
different schools okay understand so the
main quality of a master teacher
according to this list which is you know
2,000 years long is do they adjust to
the students level do they have the
ability to adjust to the students level
okay and and that's what makes you a
master teacher okay got it we talked
about it yesterday in the goals of ACI
which one is it for zero dollars were
huh yeah I'd say relevant right and
accessible okay they if they see the
audience is bored like in China they go
deeper if they see the audience's
underwater they they go more simple okay
all right okay
I always tell a joke okay just to be
honest in my American students in China
I say do you guys want to go deeper and
people scream the hole a thousand people
you know then if I stay in America you
might go deeper people are like yeah man
I mean if you wanna you know sorry okay
I still love a man okay
although if shin Jin is my also my
hometown okay next one eight nine okay
good
Tim we're gonna be on time you gotta
give me an award like half the table
okay
he's like no all right say it's a way
Dagny say way
Dagny super love super love they gotta
they gotta be made of love okay
made of love doggy means are made of
love say what means love okay and the
main meaning in the context of a teacher
is that they teach for the love of their
students and not for money get attention
get famous we were talking the teachers
we were having a fun time today telling
stories about went the minute you get up
on a stage okay and I don't care if
you're a lousy teacher I don't care if
you're bald I don't care if you're old
the audience is gonna fall in love with
you three people in the audience are
gonna fall in love with you not because
you're smart not because you're a good
teacher but because you're on the stage
you see so you gotta in English we say
you've got to keep a level head okay
Stanley okay
no like ten women are gonna fall in love
with you in the audience just cuz you're
on the stage not cuz you're a good
person
okay I'm sorry and I saw it a hundred
times
okay I've seen it many many times and I
want to warn you as a ACI teacher okay
people will get a crush on you crush
means immature
attraction they will fall in love with
you for two weeks or something then
they'll treat you bad okay so don't get
a big head don't say oh I'm so handsome
three ladies came to my room after the
talk you know they're not there for you
they're there for the teacher okay
they're there because you were on the
stage okay and every man will fall in
love with shopping and try to you know
buy you a new car and just say calm down
talk to me next week yeah and I'm just
warning you okay teach because you love
the student and don't teach for famous
or people gonna call you wonderful
people gonna offer you chocolate all day
like I did today to me you know don't
teach for those reasons it's gonna be a
mess it's gonna be a mess
okay don't teach for lower reasons don't
teach for attention for every hour of
attention you get you're gonna get
criticized for an hour on the internet
trust me okay you're gonna attract both
if you get good you will attract
jealousy okay and people will attack you
and then you're gonna freak out oh I
thought everyone loved me you know so
keep a level head okay don't get big
idea about yourself okay
you're just a instrument you know you're
just passing on the teaching you're a
bucket you're not the water how's that
okay and keep that in mind okay you'll
you'll avoid a lot of problems a lot of
disappointment so you should be at
eridanians Eridani means they teach
because they love people they teach
because they love people if a teacher
will not wash dishes don't take them as
a teacher if a teacher will not clean
the temple after the ceremony
don't take them as a teacher okay it
goes together love service
of others okay service of others
okay if they're too lazy to I don't know
build a cabin at Diamond Mountain
they're probably not teaching for the
right reason okay so now I'm just gonna
set you up for something it's time to
look like impossible to find a teacher
we're gonna talk about it okay all right
so what's number nine they teach for
love they teach for love of the student
they care about the student okay they
care about the student that means if the
student gets crazy and criticizes the
teacher and tries to hurt the teacher
the teacher still lost them okay it's
like you can't divorce your kids right I
mean probably it'd be nice right hey you
never heard of that right there's no
legal thing where you can divorce your
kid and the same in it with your
students okay disciples
once you become a teacher allama you
can't divorce them no matter how bad
they are
no matter how one day so I had a system
with Karen PJ he bought a TV and he said
you cannot have a TV and I said well why
he said I'm the Lama that was his answer
you know I'm her mama I get a TV you
don't get a TV now I'm like okay
actually I don't like TVs anyway I never
had one in my whole life I save so much
time that's why I can translate then
that we had a system if there was
something interesting on TV he would
ring his Bell he had a bell he had a
servant Bell if he rang the bell I had
to run upstairs and he said I want some
tea or I need mimosa
so the bell rang it's just if something
important on television he'll ring the
bell and I'm supposed to run upstairs
and and they're interviewing this lady
and they said is your son a good person
and she said my son is so kind is so
loving
it's so beautiful he's such a good boy
you know and I'm like why are you
ringing the bell ring but a he said this
kid just killed 17 people with a gun
this is his mom you know and she's like
he's a good boy okay you gotta be like
that with your students
okay no matter how bad they are no
matter how upset they make you they're
your kids okay you don't divorce your
kids all right
can you show your kids tough love yeah
sometimes you have to it doesn't mean I
don't love you okay it means I love you
enough to to yell at you my mama
constantly yelled at me and afterwards I
realized it's cuz he loved me he loved
me enough not to care what I think about
him you see he's not just trying to be
nice to me all the time
so he's popular you know he did what he
had to do which means a lot of bung bung
bung okay I'll put some bumps on your
head just kidding alright number 10
I'm precisely on time Tim okay say
keycode nee nee Masha Kiku nee nee match
are the Sun came up this morning out of
the butt hole of a dog so what the Sun
came up out of the butt of the dog this
morning it means something impossible
happen
so I'm finishing on time so you can try
it on get your low-tar he'll be so
impressed
what guess I did station Michael did
something this week what oh he did keep
him there Nima here check it out he'll
be so happy
ok by the way our lineage is fun ok can
remember teh guessing note our Pabon
chi-chi jongmin / - we are fun women we
have fun we tell kind of naughty jokes
and we do emptiness with fun
ok got it that's your lineage you're not
allowed to be so serious okay
alright say kill upon kill upon they
never give up on you never that that
isn't that wonderful
to be number 10 okay they will not give
up on you okay you're the bone
they're the dog you know doesn't matter
how much you hurt them how bad you are
how you mess up how many problems you
have you can go away for 20 years and
come back they will take you happily
okay they never give up on you okay
never and that's that's a llama okay all
right kill a pawn means they they never
give up on you okay all right
cocoon a Nima shy
okay
[Applause]